<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amitrajit Bose</title>
    <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Amitrajit Bose</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 23:18:10 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amitrajitbose.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Being A Mentor For Google Code-in</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/beingamentorforgooglecodein/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 23:18:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/beingamentorforgooglecodein/</guid>
      <description>About Google Code-In Google Code-In is an one of a kind online contest where pre-university students (ages 13 to 17) are invited to take part and experience open-source development. They have a wide variety of byte-sized tasks from various participating organisations, easy for beginners to jump in and get started no matter what skills they have.
What Do Mentors Do Mentors are the primary helping hands for the organisations. Mentors create tasks and look over their proper completion by the participants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Imbalanced Datasets Using SMOTE</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/smote/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 09:34:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/smote/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Close your eyes. Now imagine a perfect data world. What do you see? What do you wish to see? Exactly, me too. A flawlessly balanced dataset. A collection of data whose labels form a magnificent 1:1 ratio: 50% of this, 50% of that; not a bit to the left, nor a bit to the right. Just perfectly balanced, as all things should be. Now open your eyes, and come back to the real world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding The Sliding Window Maximum Problem</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/understanding_sliding_window_maximum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 07:41:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/understanding_sliding_window_maximum/</guid>
      <description>In this blog, I aim at explaining a very popular coding interview question to my readers, commonly known as Sliding Window Maximum, this formally goes like this
 Given an array A and an integer K. Find the maximum for each and every contiguous subarray of size K.
 Sample Input : arr = [9,6,11,8,10,5,4,13,93,14], window_size = 4 Sample Output : 11,11,11,10,13,93,93
I would be touching upon all the ineffective approaches, but would no go in depth for those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Automated Git Commands On Linux</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/how_i_automated_git_commands_on_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 14:03:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/how_i_automated_git_commands_on_linux/</guid>
      <description>How I Automated Git Commands On Linux Everytime I boot in to my system, I realise there is so much freedom I got as a user and a developer after switching from Windows to Linux. I keep wondering, how brilliant Linus Tolvards was!
I love to maintain repositories for my ongoing projects so as to keep track of my work and also a backup (FREE), if you understand what I mean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tensorflow Vs PyTorch</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/tensorflow_vs_pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 03:23:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/tensorflow_vs_pytorch/</guid>
      <description>Now that you have done quite a lot of machine learning and got those fundamentals solid, it is high time to start with neural networks and deep learning. Although you would not need it in most of the problem statements, it is like a superpower, you have complete control of how you want your network to be, how strong, how big, how weak, how cunning. Actually all you need is access to good data and lots of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Review - Intro To Tensorflow</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/course_review_dlai_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 14:54:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/course_review_dlai_1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to TensorFlow for AI, ML, &amp;amp; DL (Source: deeplearning.ai)
First and foremost, thanks to Coursera and deepLearning.ai for granting me the scholarship to take this course. I owe them. :)
I have planned to write an honest and short review about the course, I just completed it today. Things that you need to know before taking this course, whether it is suitable for you and so on. So, let us directly jump in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maze Routing - Lee&#39;s Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/maze_routing_lee_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 18:16:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/maze_routing_lee_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>What is a Maze Runner? According to Wikipedia, in electronic design automation, a maze runner is a connection routing method that represents the entire routing space as a grid. Parts of this grid are blocked by components, specialised areas, or already present wiring. The grid size corresponds to the wiring pitch of the area. The goal is to find a chain of grid cells that go from point A to point B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Neural Nets With Pytorch</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro-to-nn-pytorch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro-to-nn-pytorch/</guid>
      <description>Intro To Neural Networks with PyTorch Deep learning networks tend to be massive with dozens or hundreds of layers, that&amp;rsquo;s where the term &amp;ldquo;deep&amp;rdquo; comes from. PyTorch has a nice module nn that provides a nice way to efficiently build large neural networks. Let us together explore it in this blog.
# Import necessary packages %matplotlib inline %config InlineBackend.figure_format = &#39;retina&#39; import numpy as np import torch import helper import matplotlib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hiding Input Cells On Jupyter Notebook</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/hiding-input-cells-jupyter-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/hiding-input-cells-jupyter-notebook/</guid>
      <description>Why Needed ? Sometimes we don&amp;rsquo;t want to show the code during presentation of the notebook, or sometimes the code can look really clumsy. Taking care of the code while tearing your hairs to find a better solution to a problem simultaneously is quite a mammoth task. Most tutorials on the web would suggest you to install nbextensions, an open-source notebook extension package for Jupyter notebooks. Definitely that is clean and easy, but I just don&amp;rsquo;t like installing things and junking up my workstation, rather I&amp;rsquo;d write a custom code to solve the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Handbook</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/sqlhandbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/sqlhandbook/</guid>
      <description>SQL Handbook Author : Amitrajit Bose Data Types in Oracle SQL  VARCHAR2(size) NVARCHAR2(size) NUMBER[(precision) LONG DATE BINARY_FLOAT BINARY_DOUBLE CHAR [(size)] N.B: This tutorial uses SQLite, although most features are same as Oracle SQL and other variants  SQL Manipulation  Create Table CREATE TABLE celebs(id INTEGER, name TEXT, age INTEGER ); Insert Rows INSERT INTO celebs (id, name, age) VALUES (1, &#39;Justin Bieber&#39;, 21); Select Queries SELECT * FROM mytable; Update Value UPDATE celebs SET age = 22 WHERE id = 1; Alter Table ALTER TABLE celebs ADD COLUMN twitter_handle TEXT; Delete Rows DELETE FROM celebs WHERE twitter_handle IS NULL; Add Constraint CREATE TABLE awards (id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY, recipient TEXT NOT NULL, award_name TEXT DEFAULT &amp;quot;Grammy&amp;quot; );</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numpy 101</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/numpy101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/numpy101/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Numpy is a python library that provides functions that are especially useful when you have to work with large arrays and matrices of numeric data, like doing matrix matrix multiplications. Also, Numpy is battle tested and optimized so that it runs fast, much faster than if you were working with Python lists directly.
The array object class is the foundation of Numpy, and Numpy arrays are like lists in Python, except that every thing inside an array must be of the same type, like int or float.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dual Boot Ubuntu with Windows</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/installingubuntudualboot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/installingubuntudualboot/</guid>
      <description>Tired of the black screen on Command Prompt, enough of using the mouse to guide the pointer through the screen, you now want to code directly on the Terminal or more appropriately get a bit of that geeky feeling as a computer scientist or a budding hacker, who magically writes commands on the Terminal window and transforms the world.
Well, coming back to reality - using a Linux distribution can be one of the most liberating feeling at some times of your career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro To Database Management System</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_dbms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_dbms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To DBMS Course PPT
Schema &amp;amp; Instance  Schema - A schema is a physical or logical structure of the data-base. The basically comprise the columns along with the table. Instance - This is the actual data, when the schema is populated by real values and data entries in the form of rows.  Data Model  It is the collection of tools that describe the data. Data : The data itself is an integral part of the data-base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro To Relational Models</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_relationalmodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_relationalmodels/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To Relational Models Chapter Material
Relation - an unordered collection of attributes or fields or columns of a table.
Attributes - each column is an attribute.
Domain - set of possible values that an attribute can take.
Attribute Value - the data in a certain row and column, corresponing to a certain attribute. They are normally atomic, i.e indivisible data type. Mathematically, relation schema is a subset of multiple domain sets, or we can say a relational schema is a collection of attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>