<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dbms on Amitrajit Bose</title>
    <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/tags/dbms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dbms on Amitrajit Bose</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://amitrajitbose.github.io/tags/dbms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Handbook</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/sqlhandbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/sqlhandbook/</guid>
      <description>SQL Handbook Author : Amitrajit Bose Data Types in Oracle SQL  VARCHAR2(size) NVARCHAR2(size) NUMBER[(precision) LONG DATE BINARY_FLOAT BINARY_DOUBLE CHAR [(size)] N.B: This tutorial uses SQLite, although most features are same as Oracle SQL and other variants  SQL Manipulation  Create Table CREATE TABLE celebs(id INTEGER, name TEXT, age INTEGER ); Insert Rows INSERT INTO celebs (id, name, age) VALUES (1, &#39;Justin Bieber&#39;, 21); Select Queries SELECT * FROM mytable; Update Value UPDATE celebs SET age = 22 WHERE id = 1; Alter Table ALTER TABLE celebs ADD COLUMN twitter_handle TEXT; Delete Rows DELETE FROM celebs WHERE twitter_handle IS NULL; Add Constraint CREATE TABLE awards (id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY, recipient TEXT NOT NULL, award_name TEXT DEFAULT &amp;quot;Grammy&amp;quot; );</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro To Database Management System</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_dbms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_dbms/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To DBMS Course PPT
Schema &amp;amp; Instance  Schema - A schema is a physical or logical structure of the data-base. The basically comprise the columns along with the table. Instance - This is the actual data, when the schema is populated by real values and data entries in the form of rows.  Data Model  It is the collection of tools that describe the data. Data : The data itself is an integral part of the data-base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro To Relational Models</title>
      <link>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_relationalmodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amitrajitbose.github.io/blog/intro_relationalmodels/</guid>
      <description>Introduction To Relational Models Chapter Material
Relation - an unordered collection of attributes or fields or columns of a table.
Attributes - each column is an attribute.
Domain - set of possible values that an attribute can take.
Attribute Value - the data in a certain row and column, corresponing to a certain attribute. They are normally atomic, i.e indivisible data type. Mathematically, relation schema is a subset of multiple domain sets, or we can say a relational schema is a collection of attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>